Thinking about how to deal with Outliers is an important part of signal research.
思考如何处理离群值是信号研究的重要步骤
Let me give you a couple examples.
下面我将举几个例子
Sometimes, the prices of stocks that aren't traded very
有时候 成交量不大的股票
much undergo dramatic changes when they are actually traded.
在交易时股价波动很大
As an example, let's look at
例如 我们来看看
some small market capitalization stocks traded on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange.
在香港证交所交易的几个低市值股票
One example is Easyknit International Holdings Limited
其中一个例子是永义国际集团有限公司
which has the ticker symbol 1218.HK.
它的股票代码是 1218.HK
I'm using Easyknit as an example of a thinly or infrequently traded stock,
永义国际就属于交易量很少的股票
but what does it mean to be thinly traded.
交易量很少是什么意思？
Well, one way to quantify how much a stock is traded is to look at its typical volume.
量化股票交易量的一种方式是查看一般成交量是多少
This is the number of shares that were traded during a given time period.
成交量等于在给定时间交易的股数
However, the number of shares traded may not tell you very
但是 交易的股数并不能传递很多信息
much since a company can issue arbitrary numbers of shares.
因为公司可以发行任意股数
A better metric called turnover is the volume traded multiplied by the price per share,
另一个更好的指标是成交额 等于成交量乘以每股价格
in other words, the total amount of money that actually
换句话说 等于股票在某个期限内交易时
changed hands when the stock was traded during this period.
实际转手的总金额
This metric is more comparable across companies since it's in units of currency.
此指标更适合比较多个公司 因为它的单位是货币
Easyknit's average volume was only about
在我们制作本视频期间
10,000 shares at the time we made this video and traded at
永义国际的平均成交量只有 10,000 股
around 4.8 Hong Kong dollars for a turnover of around 48,000 Hong Kong dollars.
成交股价是 4.8 港币 成交额约为 48,000 港币
For comparison, the turnover of Tencent Holdings,
相比之下 作为中国领先的互联网服务提供商
a leading provider of Internet related services in
以及香港证交所交易最频繁的股票之一
China and one of the most traded stocks on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange,
腾讯控股的成交额
was around five billion Hong Kong dollars.
约为 50 亿港币
It doesn't take much trading to move the prices of thinly traded stocks up and down.
很低的成交量就能使成交量很少的股票股价上下波动
A single trade will cause a significant change in price,
成交一次就能使价格大幅变化
so the prices can fluctuate unpredictably.
所以股价会出人意料地波动
These fluctuations are real,
这些波动是真实的
they are due to market activity,
是由市场活动造成的
but they are unpredictable.
但是不可预测
You could avoid exposure to
为了避免这种不可预测性
this unpredictability by excluding these stocks from your trading universe.
你可以在股票池中排除这类股票
Alternatively, if you want to trade these stocks,
如果想交易这类股票
it might be a good idea to keep these price fluctuations in your trading data in
建议在交易数据中保留这些价格波动
order to be sure that your strategy performs well despite this unpredictability.
这样可以确保投资策略绩效很好 即使存在不可预测性
This example illustrates why it's important to be careful which
这个示例证明了把股票添加到
stocks you chose to include in your trading universe in the first place.
股票池中时一定要小心谨慎的原因
Including data from periods when the market is
将市场行为表现异常时期的数据
behaving in an unusual way can skew your signals.
包含在内可能会导致信号出现偏斜
For example, during and after market crashes,
例如 在崩盘期间和之后
stock prices are volatile and can reach extreme values.
股价波动性很大 可能会达到极端值
Because market crashes do not happen often,
因为崩盘很罕见
they are statistically infrequent outlying events.
所以它们在统计学上属于不常见的异常事件
If we calibrate trading signals including data from these periods,
如果我们校正交易信号并包含这一时期的数据
the results will be highly skewed and the signals
结果将高度偏斜
won't perform optimally on normal trading days,
并且信号在正常的交易日中业绩不会很好
in other words, most of the time.
也就是在绝大部分时间业绩不佳
But if we don't include such periods when calibrating trading signals,
但是如果在校正交易信号时不包括此类时期
and one of these rare events happens,
并且发生了这样的罕见事件
the signal may perform really poorly or even in a toxic manner.
信号将表现很差 甚至变成糟糕的结果
There is no golden rule to resolve this,
解决这个问题没有什么金科玉律
some traders prefer to alleviate these problems in
有些交易者会在策略制定阶段
the strategy formulation phase by
消除这些问题
controlling the sizes of the long and short positions they
他们会控制多头和空头的头寸
take and establishing thresholds called stop
并指定阈值 称为止损点
loss levels at which they will exit positions to prevent further losses.
达到止损点后 他们将平仓 防止损失阔大
It's also possible to design training strategies that
还可以设计交易策略
attempt to take advantage of sudden extreme price movements.
通过瞬时的极端价格变动获利
People who trade with so-called contrarian strategies
利用反向策略的交易者
seek to identify sudden price movements or
会寻找某些特殊的股价变动或者紊乱
dislocations that they think are not justified by
他们认为这些变动或紊乱
real information or events and therefore won't last,
不合乎股票真实信息和事件 所以不会持续
and they trade against such movements.
他们会基于这类变动进行反向交易
One could try to apply this strategy to data of any level of time resolution,
交易者可以将此策略应用到任何时间范围的数据
but minute level data are more prone to
但是分钟级数据比每日数据或每月数据
these sudden movements than daily data or monthly data.
更容易受到此类突发变动的影响
This is a risky strategy,
这种策略风险很大
it can be difficult to determine whether the price will settle back to where it was,
如果股价会回到之前的水平
in which case the trader profits,
这时候交易者将获利
or whether the price will continue to move in
但若股价继续朝着相同的方向变化
the same direction which would not benefit the trader.
这种情况对交易者不利